快看，你们一定不信
Hey! You're not gonna believe this.
是的，我们知道那里面 有裸女的照片
Yes,Ross,we know they have magazines with pictures of naked women in them.
别告诉他还有出录影带
Don't tell him about the videos!
我编了一则笑话寄到花花公子 结果登出来了
I made up a joke and sent it in to Playboy.They printed it.
我不知道花花公子也登笑话
I didn't know they print jokes.
他们有笑话、专访 爆炸性新闻，并非只有图片
They print jokes,interviews,hard-hitting journalism.It's not just about the pictures.
妈妈不吃这一套，我们也一样
Didn't work on Mom,it's not gonna work on us.
你们看，还是第一则
Check it out. It's the first one.Right there.
真好笑，我编出来时也很好笑
That is funny.It was also funny when I made it up.
什么？ 这则笑话是我编的
-What? -I made that joke up.
不是你，是我
No,you didn't. I did.
是我，我说给丹听 他说这是他听过最好笑的笑话
Yes,I did. I told Dan and he said it was the funniest joke he'd ever heard.
帮我谢谢丹
Hey,tell Dan thanks.
怎样？
What?
抱歉，我在看下面那则笑话 那则很好笑
I was just reading the joke below it. Man,that one is funny.
莫妮卡，你记得 我跟你说过那则笑话吧？
Monica,you remember me telling you that joke,right?
不记得 真的不记得？
-No. -Seriously?
你的笑话一大堆
You tell a lot of jokes.
钱德，那是我的笑话
Look,it's my joke.
不过如果告诉你他们没有印投稿人，也许你会好受些
But if it makes you feel better,they don't print the name.
所以是谁的并不重要，对吧？ 大概吧
-So it doesn't really matter who gets credit. -Yeah,I guess.
你们好 乔伊，花花公子登了我的笑话
-Hey,guys. -Playboy printed my joke!
不，那是我的笑话 你打电话去问就知道
No,it's mine! Call them! They'll tell you!
那是我的笑话 是我的 嘿嘿嘿
-My joke! -My joke!Whoa,whoa,whoa!
笑话？ 什么？ 你们知道这上面有裸女吧？
Jokes? What...?You know there's naked chicks in there,right?
本集播出：“笑话”
The One With The Joke
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
快，赶快转到“音乐内幕”
Dude! You have got to turn on Behind The Music.
红心合唱团状况百出 可能会解散
The band Heart is having a tough time and they may break up.
我们去你家看
Let's watch that at your place.
不行，莫妮卡在看烹饪节目 快点，我想看她们瘦的时候
Monica's watching a show. I don't want to miss when they were skinny.
钱德，你知道吗？ 我们应该去买新墨镜
Hey,Chandler? You know what we should do?You and I should go out and get some new sunglasses.
什么？不要，我想看电视
What? No,I want to watch this.
你的有线电视断了吗？
-Did your cable go out? -No. No,that's VH1.
不是，那是VH1（专门播放音乐录影带的电视台）
-No. No,that's VH1.
现在的小朋友听的音乐对我来说都只是噪音
I tell you,the music these kids listen to today it's a lot of noise to me.
乔伊，有线电视为什么没了？
Why is your cable out?
因为我没交费
Oh,because I haven't really paid the bill.
你若缺钱，拜托让我借给你好吗
If you need money,would you please let me loan you some?
不要，你别再说了好吗
No,Chandler. Forget about it,okay?
我知道吉宁走后，我有点吃紧
I know things have been tight since Janine moved out.
天哪，她可真辣
God,was she hot.
就是啊
I know,yeah.
但是我可以应付，好吗？ 我可以听广播
Look,I can handle it,all right? I can listen to the radio.
罗斯也给了我一本很棒的书
And Ross gave me this great book.
要不要问那个笑话小偷 我们能不能去他家看电视？
Want to see if the joke stealer will let us watch at his place?
好啊
Sure.
电话费有交吗？ 没有
-Paid your phone bill? -No.
原来是你
It's only you.
你们在看什么？ 我们在看花花公子
-What are you doing? -Looking at a Playboy.
我也想看
I want to look too!
好恶
Yikes!
这些照片是有故事性吗？
Do you think these pictures are trying to tell a story?
当然有，像这位年轻小姐
Sure. Like in the case of this young woman...
她的衣服不见了，所以…
she has lost her clothes.
她光溜溜的骑着马大喊 “我的衣服呢？”
So she rides naked on the horse,she's crying out,"Where are they?"
只是这样躺在草地上是找不到的
She's not gonna find them,lying in the grass like that.
记不记得以前去谷仓 掀起衣服翘起屁股的日子？
Remember the days when you'd go out to the barn...Lift up your shirt and bend over?
不过我会约这个女生 她很可爱，很阳光
You see,now,I would date this girl.She's cute,she's outdoorsy.
而且她会生火，可以派上用场
And she knows how to build a fire. That'll come in handy.
我有一个问题
I got a question.
如果要在我们当中挑女朋友 你们会挑谁？
If you had to pick one of us to date,who would it be?
不知道
-I don't know.
我也不知道 瑞秋
-Me neither.Rachel.
什么？
What?
不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
Me neither.
我都忘了红心合唱团 有那么多经典
You know,you forget how many great songs Heart had.
“梭子鱼” 是我练键盘学的第一首歌
"Barracuda" was the first song I learned to play on the keyboard.
你听过，弹过 所以那首歌是你写的？
So you heard it,you repeated it...so that must mean you wrote it.
你们怎么还争啊？老实说
You guys with this joke. Well,I gotta say...
我有大笑，但是我看不太懂
I know I cracked up,but I'm not even sure I got it.
什么？
What?
你看不懂？那个医生是只猴子
You didn't get it?The doctor is a monkey.
猴子没办法开处方
And monkeys can't write out prescriptions.
我的笑话不准你笑
You are not allowed to laugh at my joke.
你的笑话？海夫纳（花花公子创办人）可不同意
Your joke?Well,I think the Hef would disagree.
所以他寄了这张支票给我，一百美元
Which is why he sent me a check...for $100.
你偷我的笑话，还偷我的钱
So you stole my joke and you stole my money?
我本来想直接存进自动柜员机的
I was gonna stick it in the ATM.
现在我决定让那位性感银行女职员 知道我是个作家
But now I think I'll show the sexy teller...that I am a published writer.
她会知道你是偷来的
She'll know that you stole the joke.
你想怎样，跟着我去吗？ 没错
You gonna follow me there?-Yeah.
反正我现在又不去 好
-I'm not gonna go now. -Okay.
你的帐单
Here you go.
甘瑟，我现在不能付
Gunther?I can't pay now,
我没工作 得节省不必要的开销
because I'm not working.I've had to cut down on some luxuries like...
像付帐之类的
paying for stuff,so....
如果你愿意的话，你可以来这里工作
Well,if you want,you can work here.
我不晓得…只是
I don't know.It's just....
我演过连续剧，你知道的
See,I was a regular on a soap opera,you know?
从明星到服务生，我实在…
And to go from that to this,it's just....
而且还得招呼我的朋友
And plus,I'd have to wait on all my friends.
好，但薪水很高 还可以随时看瑞秋看个够
Okay. But the money's good.Plus,you get to stare at Rachel as much as you want.
什么？
What?
工作时间有弹性
Flexible hours.
也许可以喔，可以用电话吗？
Maybe I could be a waiter.Could I use the phone?
她选瑞秋
She picked Rachel.
她想改口 但是很明显，她选瑞秋
She tried to back out of it,but it was obvious. She picked Rachel.
他偷了我的笑话，就这样偷了
He took my joke. He just took it.
这样是不对的 还有什么是不对的？
This is wrong. You know what else is wrong?
菲比选了瑞秋 知道还有谁会选瑞秋吗？
Phoebe picking Rachel.Know who else picked Rachel?
罗斯，知道罗斯还做了什么吗？ 他偷了我的笑话
Ross.Know what else Ross did? He stole my joke.
我要买一本笑话日志
I'm gonna get a joke journal,you know?
记录我每次讲笑话的日期时间
And document the date and time of every single one of my jokes.
好主意
Good idea.
你知道什么主意不好吗？
Know what's a bad idea?
选择瑞秋 没错
Picking Rachel. -That's right.
什么声音？
Did you hear something?
也许是罗斯爬进我的脑袋 窃取我的思绪
Maybe it's the sound of Ross climbing into my brain to steal my thoughts.
是客厅传来的
It's coming from the living room.
我的书看完了
I finished my book.
你们好
-Hey,you guys. -Hey.
你们好可爱
Don't you guys look cute.
真是可爱的一对
You guys make a cute couple.
莫妮卡，你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
没什么 我只是想制造出前两天的乐趣
Just trying to re-create some of the fun that we had at my place.
就是你选瑞秋不选我那次 多好玩啊
Remember? When you picked Rachel over me?That was funny.
是蛮好玩的 一点也不好玩
-It was kind of funny. -It wasn't funny at all!
你为什么选她？ 为什么不选我？
Why would you do that?Why didn't you pick me?
好，我之所以比较倾向瑞秋
Fine.The reason I was leaning a little bit more toward Rachel than you...
是因为你…有点难搞 我们去吃饭吧
is just,you know,you're...high maintenance. Let's go to lunch!
哪有这回事，你觉得我难搞？
That is completely untrue.You think I'm high maintenance?
证明给我看，你列一张清单 我们逐条讨论
Prove it.You write out a list,and we'll go through it point by point.
你说得对，你很好相处
No,you're right,you're easygoing.
你只是没有瑞秋那么好相处 她比较有弹性，比较圆融
You're just not as easygoing as Rachel. She's just more...flexible and mellow. That's all.
每个人都不一样
Well,people are different.
瑞秋什么都好 怎么欺负她都行
Rachel will do whatever you want. You can just walk all over her.
慢着，你是说我没个性吗？ 我才没有
What? Are you saying that I'm a pushover? I'm not a pushover.
好，你有个性
Oh,okay. You're not a pushover.
天哪，你觉得我没个性
You think I'm a pushover.
你听着，我们不跟你吃饭了
Well,watch this.You're not invited to lunch!
怎么样？够强硬了吧？ 莫妮卡，我们去吃饭
What do you think? Pretty strong,I think.Come on,Monica,let's go to lunch.
把清单列出来
You start working on that list.
她真让人难以置信 就是啊，你想吃什么？
-I cannot believe her. -I know. Where do you want to eat?
我很喜欢那家日本料理
-Oh,I love that Japanese place.
我吃腻日本菜了，不要去那家 那你想去哪里你决定吧
-I'm sick of Japanese. Not there.Wherever you want to go is cool.
甘瑟，你看
Oh,hey,Gunther...check this out.
那个钱德真的很好笑
Yeah,that Chandler cracks me up.
罗斯，你要喝什么吗？ 我要去柜台
You want anything to drink? I'm heading up there.
要，我要咖啡，谢了 不客气
-I'll take a coffee. Thanks. -Sure.
咖啡？ 不要
-Coffee? -No.
要咖啡吗？我要去柜台 不用了
Coffee? I'm going up there.No,thank you.
需要什么吗？我要去柜台
You need anything? I'm heading up there.
我要一杯冰水 没问题
I'd love ice water.You got it.
乔伊，你在干什么？ 表示友善啊
What are you doing?Just being friendly.
乔伊，你不能去柜台后面
You're not supposed to go back there.
没关系啦，对吧，甘瑟？
It's okay. Right?
别跟我使眼色
Don't wink at me.
把围裙穿上
And put on your apron.
穿就穿 你怎么不叫其他客人穿围裙
Okay.I don't see you asking other paying customers to put on aprons.
乔伊，你在这里打工吗？ 没有
-Joey,do you work here? -No.
服务生 什么事？
-Waiter. -Yeah!
乔伊，怎么回事？ 你为什么不告诉我们？
What's going on? Why didn't you tell us you work here?
这件事蛮尴尬的
It's kind of embarrassing.
我之前是演员，现在是服务生 一般应该反过来才对
I mean,I was an actor,now I'm a waiter.It's supposed to go the other direction.
你的围裙也反穿成披风了
So's your apron. You're wearing it like a cape.
这份工作很简单，薪水很高
I mean,the job's easy and the money's good,you know?
反正我都在这混，干脆赚个钱
I guess if I'm hanging out here,I might as well get paid for it.
只是要招呼你们感觉很怪
I just feel kind of weird serving you guys,you know?
乔伊，我也做过，还好啊
It'll be great.Come on,I did it and it was fine.
对啊，怎么会怪？ 乔伊，帮我端个咖啡
Why would it be weird?Hey,Joey? Can I get some coffee?
确实没那么怪
It doesn't seem that weird.
我说真的，我点的咖啡还没来
I asked before. You still haven't gotten it.
现在又变怪了
See,now it's weird again.
你来这里工作是好事 你会赚大钱，给你一个忠告
You're gonna make a lot of money. Here's your first tip.
不要学坏
Don't eat yellow snow.
2点15分，咖啡馆
2:15,coffeehouse.
太好了 总算有人能传承我的智慧
This is great. Finally,someone I can pass my wisdom to.
告诉你几件我在这里学到的事
Let me tell you some things I learned working here.
首先，顾客永远是对的
First,the customer is always right.
微笑能让你无往不利
A smile goes a long way.
有人对你不客气 就朝松饼打喷嚏
And if anyone is ever rude to you,sneeze muffin.
谢了
Thanks,Rach.
你们对我真好
Hey,look,you guys are just terrific,you know?
可不可以清场，好让别的客人进来？ 有流动才有商机
How about clearing out so I can get some new customers?It's all about turnover.
乔伊，我要的咖啡呢
Seriously,can I get my coffee?
抱歉，马上来 我送你一块松饼做补偿
I'm sorry. I'll get it right now.And since you waited,I'll toss in a free muffin.
菲比，我们想跟你谈谈
Phoebe,we'd like to talk to you.
好
Okay.
或许我是有点难搞 或许瑞秋是有点没个性
So,maybe I am a little high maintenance.And maybe Rachel is a little bit of a pushover.
但你知道你是什么吗？
But you know what you are?
很抱歉这么说 但是你，菲比，是个怪人
We are sorry to tell you this,but you,Phoebe,are flaky.
没错，我是很怪
That's true,I am flaky.
所以你怪也无所谓？ 完全无所谓
So,what,you're just okay with being flaky?Yeah,totally.
那我难搞也无所谓 我没个性也无所谓
Then I'm okay with being high maintenance.Yeah. And I am okay with being a pushover.
太好了，无所谓就好
That's great. Good for you guys.
我才不难搞 我才没有没个性
-I am not high maintenance! -I am not a pushover!
谁说你们是了？ 你啊
-Who said you were? -You did!
我是怪人，专门乱说话
I'm flaky. I'll say anything.
甘瑟
Hey,Gunther.
可不可以替我一下，我接到试镜通知
Can you cover for me? I got an audition.
不行，我要去染头发
No,I'm leaving to get my hair dyed.
是吗？我喜欢你的自然色
I like your natural color.
拜托啦，这是个好角色
It's a great part.
我演男主角的好友 在酒吧帮他占位子，你听
I'm the lead guy's best friend.I wait for him and save his seat. Listen.
抱歉，这个位子有人
"I'm sorry,that seat's saved."
就这样？ 或许不是他的好友，但是…
-That's the whole part? -Maybe he's not his best friend.
1小时后见
I'll see you.
上帝啊
Oh,man.
我绝对能拿到那个角色 抱歉，这个位子有人
I could totally get that part. "I'm sorry,this seat is taken."
抱歉 不，我不是说你
-Excuse me. -No,I didn't mean you.
但你以为是真的吧？ 我以为你在帮别人占位
But you believed me?I believed you were saving this seat for someone.
所以你会雇用我？
So you'd hire me,right?
用你干嘛？
For what?
就是说嘛…各位请注意 本店要暂停营业1小时
Exactly! All right,everybody listen up!The coffeehouse will be closed for about an hour.
什么？
What?
好帮助孩子们远离毒品
It's for the kids.Yeah,to keep the kids off drugs.
这是本期花花公子的重要报导 各位一定都看过
It's a very important issue in this month's Playboy.I'm sure you all read about it.
你不想让孩子们远离枪支吗？
Hey! Don't you wanna keep guns away from kids?
你刚才说毒品 这是恶性循环，滚啦
-You said,"drugs." -It's a vicious cycle. Get out!
快点
Go!
那是我的笑话 是我的
-It's my joke. -It's my joke.
是我的
It's my joke.
我们再吵也吵不出结果
I don't think we're gonna settle this.
让莫妮卡决定吧 好
Let's have Monica decide.
莫妮卡，出来一下
-Hey,Mon! -Get out here!
莫妮卡
-Monica? -Okay.
你来决定这个笑话是谁的
You have to decide whose joke this is.
为什么要我决定？ 因为你才能客观公正
Why do I have to?You're the only one that can be fair.
我不能，你是我的男朋友
I can't be. You're my boyfriend.
但我是你哥哥，我们是家人 世上最重要的就是亲情
But I'm your brother. We're family.That's the most important thing in the world.
不要想左右她
Don't try to sway her.
只有我能让你生小孩
I'm your only chance to have a baby.
我们开始吧
-Okay,let's go. -All right.
我们会说出这个笑话的由来 你再决定谁说的是实话…是我
We'll each tell you how we came up with the joke...then you decide which one of us is telling the truth. Me.
钱德，你先
Chandler,you first.
好，我是2个月前 跟史提夫吃饭时想到的
I thought of the joke two months ago at lunch with Steve.
就是圣诞节遇见的那家伙吗？
-Did I meet him at Christmas?
让我说完好吗？ 你要我选你吗？
-Can I finish?-You want me to pick you?
我绝对不会那样凶你
See,I would never snap at you like that.
两个孩子
Two babies.
请继续
-Continue. -Okay.
史提夫说他去看医生 他的医生姓侯奇
Steve said he had to go to the doctor. And his doctor's name is Dr. Mompey.
我说“猴子医生？” 所以才会有猴子医生这个笑话
I said,"Dr. Monkey?" And that is how the whole Dr. Monkey thing came up.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
我是念进化论的 记得吧？进化。猴子进化成人？
Okay,look,I study evolution.Remember? Evolution.Monkey into man.
况且我是博士，我还养过猴子
Plus,I'm a doctor. And...I had a monkey.
我是猴子博士
I'm Dr. Monkey!
这点我不跟你争
I'm not arguing with that.
好，可以了，我决定好了
I've heard enough for my decision.
太好了，结果是什么  快说
-Okay,so what..? -Do tell.
你们两个都是白痴
You are both idiots.
那个笑话不但不好笑 还冒犯了女性
It's not funny. And it's offensive to women.
还有医生，还有猴子
And doctors. And monkeys.
你们不该争笑话是谁的
You shouldn't argue over who gets credit.
应该争是谁让这世界受这种罪
You should argue over who gets blamed for inflicting this joke on the world.
别再争了，那个笑话烂透了
Now,let it go.The joke sucks.
那是你的笑话 才不是
-It's your joke. -It is not.
钱德，你在这里
-Oh,my God,Chandler,there you are. -Hi.
是菲比和瑞秋
Hey,it's Phoebe and Rachel.
你要不要告诉她们 你刚才说我并不难搞？
Why don't you tell them what you told me about me not being high maintenance.
莫妮卡是个自信沉着的女性
Monica is a self-sufficient,together lady.
跟她在一起就像在度假
Being with her has been like being on a vacation.
至于所谓的难搞 只是注重小细节和…
And what may be perceived as high maintenance...is merely attention to detail and
心灵的慷慨
generosity of spirit.
这真是我所听过最棒的假话
Wow. You know what? That is the best fake speech I think I've ever heard.
真的？我听过更棒的
Really? I've heard better.
等等，那是他自己说的 你告诉她们
Wait,he came up with that himself. Tell them.
我已经没词了 可以重复吗？
I'm out of words. Should I say it again?
我一点也不难搞，一点也不，钱德
Look,I am not high maintenance! I am not. Chandler!
你是有点难搞
You're a little high maintenance.
你上黑名单了
You are on my list!
对不起，你并不好相处 但你很热情，这样很好
Look,I'm sorry,but you're not..You're not easygoing,but you're passionate.And that's good.
当你为小事不高兴时 我觉得我很能安抚你的
And when you get upset about little things,I think I'm pretty good at making you feel better.
那样也很好
That's good too.
所以她们说你难搞也行 因为我喜欢…
They say you're high maintenance，but it's okay,because I like
搞定你
maintaining you.
我没叫他说这些
I didn't tell him that.
你从黑名单除名了 我除名了
-You're off my list. -I'm off the list.
菲比
Phoebe?
你不找我当女朋友也没关系 因为我有最棒的男朋友
It's okay that you don't want me to be your girlfriend.I have the best boyfriend.
我突然觉得你好迷人
You know,suddenly I find you very attractive.
兄弟，试镜结果如何？
How'd the audition go?
不好，我没拿到那个角色 这里的工作也没了，所以…
Oh,not good. No.I didn't get the part. And I lost my job here,so...
好惨烈的试镜
Wow,that is a bad audition.
这里的工作为什么没了？
Well,how did you lose your job here?
我要去试镜，但甘瑟叫我留下 他好去染头发
I had the audition but Gunther said I had to stay so he could get his hair dyed.
但我还是去了，他就炒我鱿鱼
So I went anyway,and he fired me.
他扔下工作去办私事 叫才来2天的你留下负责？
He left work to do a personal errand...and left you in charge when you've been here two days?
这样不对吧 但是能怎么办？
That's not right.What are you gonna do?
乔伊，你不能就这么算了
You can't let him get away with that.
我绝不放过他，我要去教训他
I won't let him get away with that. I'm gonna say..
不，我不该多事
I shouldn't say anything.
不，我要去教训他
No,I should say something!
甘瑟，让乔伊继续在这里打工 你这样解雇他一点也不…
-Gunther? I want you to give Joey his job back.It's not fair that you have to fire..
好
-Okay.
什么？ 他可以继续打工
-What? -He can have his job back.
没错，他可以继续打工
That's right,he can have his job back.
很高兴我们讲通了
Glad we got that all straightened out.
好了，你可以继续打工了
There you go,Joey.Got your job back.
太好了，谢谢你
-That's great. Thanks.
不赖吧？谁没个性了？
Pretty nice,huh? Now who's a pushover?
你坐到我的位子了 抱歉
-Rach,you're in my seat. -I'm sorry.
你们都没说会找谁当女朋友
I never heard who you'd pick to be your girlfriend.
我选你 没错，绝对是你
-I'd pick you,Phoebe. -Yeah,definitely you,Phoebe.
我也这么觉得
Yeah,I kind of thought.
-绝不可能  -肯定选你
-Never. -It would totally be you.
我有一个问题
I have a question
如果要找另外两个人当男朋友 你们会找谁？
If you had to pick one of the other two to go out with...who would you pick?
少来
-No way.
我拒绝回答  乔伊
-I'm not answering.Joey.
少来，我拒绝回答
No way,I'm not answering that.